XU WEIWEN

Phone: +1 (706) 308-1017 | Email: wx37523@uga.edu

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Artificial Intelligence student, had experience on computer vision before, now focuses on machine learning, deep learning for image processing. Strong programming ability and knowledge about machine learning and deep learning. Curious about research and motivated in developing end products. Interested in data science and analysis as career goal.

SKILLS

- Strong Programming Skills in Python, JAVA, C, C++, Objective C, SQL, Javascript, PHP, HTML5, CSS3, Prolog
- Proficient in IDE, Xcode, Android Studio, OpenCV, Visual Studio
- Other experience: Tensorflow, Keras, Tableau, Spark, Unity, Jmonkey, Blender

PROJECTS

- Image Analysis and Signal Processing: Cilia Segmentation

 Analyzing cilia beating frequencies for cilia segmentation with medical videos
- Time series Analysis: Web Traffic Time Series Forecasting of Wiki Webpages
 Long short-term memory (LSTM) model applied to 145k wiki pages in python
- NLP and Large Data: Text Document Classification and Malware Classification
 Apply naïve Bayes classifier on text classification and random forest classifier on malware classification. Implemented on pySpark with both NLP classification projects.
- Image Analysis: *Neuron Segmentation Project and Facial Expression Classification*Apply CNNs with Python and Tensorflow for Neuron segmentation. Apply HOG and SVM for expression classification.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist Student Assistant, 10/2018 till now

UGA ITOS - Athens, USA

- Data engineering transforming raw data into clean and constructed data
- Construct interactive data visualization for client using Qlik

Image Processing Summer Intern, 06/2018 to 08/2018

Coherent AI – Shenzhen, China

- Vehicle detection in traffic images with deep learning model
- Hyperspectral image reconstruction from 3 channel images with deep learning model

Web IT and Volunteer, 10/2015 to 06/2017

The Brain Charity - Liverpool, United Kingdom

• Front-end web development with HTML, CSS and Javascript using the Joomla content management system.

IT Support, 10/2014 to 06/2015

Xi'an Jiaotong-Liverpool University - Suzhou, China

- Worked as a receptionist in IT support center handling hardware and software problems that students brought.
- Supported maintenance of university printers.

EDUCATION

Master of Science: Artificial Intelligence, 08/2017-05/2019

University of Georgia - Athens, GA, USA

• Topics: Data analysis, pattern recognition, machine learning, deep learning, computer vision, image processing

Bachelor of Science(Honors): Artificial Intelligence, 2015-2017 University of Liverpool - Liverpool, UK

- Topics: Software development and engineering, Robotics, multi-agent system, game developing
- First degree achieved. (converting to GPA: 3.77/4)

Bachelor of Science: Information and Computer Science, 2013-2015

XJTLU - Suzhou China

- Google Developer Group Suzhou: volunteer for introducing cutting edge technology to students.
- IT Club in XJTLU: head of the propaganda department.

PUBLICATION

Co-auther: Y. Lu, X. Huang, B. Huang, Weiwen Xu, Q. Zhang, R. Xu, D. Liu., "A Study on the Reliability of Software Defined Wireless Sensor Network," 2015 IEEE International Conference on Smart City, Chengdu, China, Dec 19-21, 2015.